hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and on this podcast I help you
grow in your life and your business
change your habits and start doing the
things that are actually going to bring
in money as a course Critter coach
trainer and Mentor because honestly
being broke and trying to help people
are not a good recipe together and if
you want to have impact you need to also
bring in the bag and bring in a ton of
cash in your business that's what I'm
going to show you how to do is what to
do to be able to be successful
financially and have crazy amounts of
impact we've helped clients make tens of
millions of dollars in coaching online
and have impact with hundreds of
thousands of people around the world yet
I hear people often say well I just want
to have impact Jeremiah I don't want to
make a lot of money truth is you're not
going to have the impact that you want
to make unless you bring in a certain
amount of money don't be living in a
fantasy land that tells you that that
you can
start bringing in the cash flow that you
want so that you can actually start to
reach the people that you're meant to
reach and meant to impact now today I
want to talk about communication and I
want to talk about kind of a
multi-dimensional topic of when we're
communicating when we're selling
ourselves when we're in coaching when
you're connecting with people you're
always selling yourself you're always
connecting with people that they're
making a decision do I buy from this
person or do I ignore them and so in our
communication with people in our
leadership style and the way that we
work there are certain ways of
communicating
that will turn people off because they
will perceive you as insecure and
someone who doesn't believe in what
they're talking about
one of the biggest ones is defending
yourself when somebody is a naysayer and
you're defending yourself or putting a
disclaimer on everything that you're
saying meaning you need to uh defend
yourself before somebody can attack you
before somebody can misunderstand you
that you are setting up okay I'm gonna
speak my truth but then I'm going to
tell you the five reasons that I didn't
mean this
I'm sorry but that that that
communication style I used to do that
um it comes from massive insecurity
massive worry and fear about it people
misunderstand you what might happen
getting hurt by other people or this
need to always say the perfect thing and
for people to always understand you some
crazy perfectionistic need that if if
people don't understand you that things
are are wrong and bad now the truth is
you're responsible for people
understanding you for people connecting
with your message for people connecting
with the words that you're saying
to defend yourself and disclaimer
everything you say is the complete
opposite of doing that because you truly
don't actually believe in what you're
saying when you say that or at least if
you do it's going to come across that
you don't and you're going to look like
the the biggest idiot on the farm who
doesn't know what they're talking about
by constantly disclaiming themselves
here's a great example of this since
everybody loves examples is saying well
here's the thing I don't believe that
um
course creators
who sell online are
unethical people
except for the ones that are unethical
and except for the ones that are
stealing and just so you know I I mean
that like they they have to be this way
and don't misinterpret me I understand
that what I mean is that like doing that
horse and pony show after every single
thing that you say where you're trying
to explain one sentence with five ten
thousand paragraphs of what you actually
meant by it comes across as you having
no confidence you being somebody that
nobody should respect truthfully is
nobody respects a person who
communicates and talks that way because
they see that it's easy to run all over
people
and so when you learn to just say say
Your Truth say what you want and not
care
if people misunderstand you not worry if
they misunderstand you if they
misunderstand you then you come back to
the drawing board and evaluate it later
see it's this fear and worry of actually
having to come back to the drawing board
and not being perfect every single time
that you put stuff out there that causes
people to do that
give it up let people misunderstand you
let them think that you meant something
different
why is it so important that they don't
it's not life or death I promise you
that
especially if you're building a business
a course creation business listen I get
it if in your in your previous job maybe
in an abusive relationship maybe in an
old friendship a toxic friendship maybe
you were in a situation where people re
required you to logically tear down
every argument that they said every time
and prove and validate yourself in every
conversation you have I I am sorry that
you have been around such that
treated you that way that made you do
that because that's what it is is there
are rude mean bullying people that made
you do that if you're somebody that
feels like you need to constantly be
defending yourself constantly
disclaiming yourself every time you open
your mouth and like you literally can't
say like like like I've seen people do
this one sentence and then a thousand
like a hundred sentences of disclaimers
and that's their that's their point and
I'm like just say the one sentence and
then let five people misunderstand it
just say the one sentence and then let
other people misunderstand it and that's
the thing is really coming to grips with
why we're so terrified of people
misunderstanding
why we need people to understand us the
first time and that violent need to
control other people's thoughts
that's what it is
it's a it's a need to forcibly control
the way that other people perceive hear
us and view us that's all it is
instead of just letting people think
things that are not true because they
can think them
and so as a communicator as a coach as a
course creator as somebody that's going
out there to launch your business to
reach new people out there if you're
constantly disclaiming and defending
yourself and trying to forcibly control
the thought patterns of everybody that
you're reaching nobody's going to want
to do business with you nobody's going
to buy a single thing you sell nobody's
going to want to purchase anything from
you because you're you're not fun to be
around when you do that
people who do that who every single
thing that they they constantly have to
defend well I wasn't talking about that
well that wasn't relevant to me well
that wasn't this people who constantly
have to to beat into everybody around
them their version of themselves how
they want to be perceived
of like well I was this way this wasn't
relevant to me I didn't mean that this
is what I meant this is what I mean
don't misunderstand me this is truly how
it is and constantly trying to it's it's
massive massive massive insecurity
and it's completely related to this
worry and fear that if people don't
understand perfectly the first time what
you mean that bad things will happen in
your life that's that's what it is
because you wouldn't be doing it if you
didn't think that it had a positive
outcome
people every behavior that we do as
humans subconsciously We Believe has
some kind of a positive influence and
outcome in our lives
and so if in your job if in your
workplace if in your corporate or your
relationship you had to do that for
safety security to climb the ladder to
be respected to be understood
let it go this isn't that world and when
it comes to you connecting with your
Target customer you want to learn to use
as few words as possible to get your
point across
that's one of the biggest problems with
course creators and coaches they're
using way too many words to tell people
what they really mean because they're
trying to make sure that everybody knows
exactly what they mean I'm sorry but let
people misunderstand you let people
assume the wrong thing and then answer
them later if they ask you a question I
would rather actually say the wrong
thing five times in a presentation
and then have somebody bring up hey is
this what you meant and then answer it
and address it then have to spend a a
100 times more hours disclaiming myself
ahead of time
by precursoring everything that I'm
saying by Imagine by by preventing any
possibility that things won't go within
accordance to how I want it to again
it's a deep hyper level of control is
the only reason why people do that and
and we may not think that it's control
but that's exactly what it is because
we're trying to to
tightly grip
how everything goes in our lives
let go
of the outcomes let go of what people
think about you let go of other people
and let them leave you let them hate you
let them dislike you let them not agree
with you
without you having to make an argument
to get them on your side
to get them to come in alignment with
your way of thinking or your viewpoint
you've never done that before in your
life you
should start because your relationships
your business are gonna get a lot better
by doing that listen I get it in
corporate
in in in in maybe how you've lived your
life up to this moment in time
this is coming from somebody who's been
successful in business and worked with
some of the top coaches and course
creators in the world and they will they
will all attest to this
exact thing that I'm telling you
stop defending yourself stop trying to
control the perceptions that other
people have of you so stinking hard
and just be yourself just talk how you
want to without worry or fear about how
other people might see you
because that's how you're actually going
to attract more authentic relationships
that's how you're really truly going to
connect with people
maybe you go around and you compliment
everybody because you you're wanting to
be seen or perceived as a caring person
who cares literally now it's nice to
compliment people it's nice to to share
that with people but when you got 10 000
people in front of you like it's
completely impractical illogical and
impossible to do that at scale and
here's what I would recommend doing is
in this in this business
imagine that you have 3 000 customers
even when you only have one and then
operate out of the same boundaries
because you're going to have to retrain
people and you're going to piss a lot of
people off they're going to want their
money back if you have one level of
boundary that's different for just one
client and now you're gonna have to
change it as you go it becomes a lot
harder to do that instead of setting the
heavy boundaries up front
with what you are actually capable of
doing imagine what your physical human
self is capable of doing with 3 000
people following you now do that with
one person following you
it's not practical to personally message
every single morning every single person
that you like it's just ridiculous
like break up with the codependency
psychosis mindset that you need to be
inside of everybody's business all the
time
that you need to make everybody think
good things about you all the time when
you can do this you're you will scale
your business your coaching business
will grow your course business will grow
when you give up trying to so tightly
mind melt everybody's opinions about you
into positivity and positive thoughts
about you let people think negative
thoughts about you let them think bad
thoughts about you they are entitled to
that as human beings and here's the
kicker here's the reason why
what it's going to take for you to
actually work the five steps to build
your business we talk about the five
steps
finding your Niche writing your offer
copy creating your landing pages
launching analyzing the reports and then
repeating
you will not have the mental or time
capacity
to
worry so much about other people's
perceptions of you if you're actually
working those five steps
if you are spending your energy so
focused on making people like you you
will never do those five steps because
you you will be so focused on
time wasting time sucking life
destroying activity it really is it's a
life-destroying activity to try to
manage and maintain other people's
perceptions of us to try to manage and
maintain what they think about us to try
to manage and maintain making everybody
have positive rainbow colored thoughts
about us all the time
instead just be you show up as you be
bold be courageous and don't be
expending energy and hours of your
working time
trying to tightly control what others
think about you when you do that you can
flow because then you can put out a
piece of content without processing
through is this piece of content gonna
land right
I never consider if a piece of content
is going to land right
never
I used to and my business didn't grow
the most successful coaches and course
creators that I know don't they move
away from
that need to be so cautious
and it's not even about being cautious
it's literally it's about control it's
about tightly taking people's brains and
saying you will think this way about me
or and nothing else is how you will
think if you are that focused on
controlling the mental thought patterns
of other human beings you won't be
successful in business
you won't and so you have to get rid of
trying to make people like you trying to
make people think nice things about you
trying to make people say nice things
about you and just
put yourself out there without any
consideration as to how you're going to
be perceived how they're going to see
you throw all caution to the wind be
Reckless with it
and then learn to have control over when
you go back to some of these old
patterns of trying to control
perceptions that you put up a stop sign
you say you know what I'm not going to
do that because that behavior does not
serve me for my goals it does not serve
me to increase my income and even if
it's been my habit for 30 40 50 years I
am now choosing to no longer do what
I've done my whole life because I'm
doing this thing for the coaching and
course business you have to take beliefs
and patterns and habits of how you've
lived your life if you want to increase
your income in this business and so what
I'm telling you is stuff that works it's
stuff that will radically change how you
look at the world around you how much
energy you have because if you're
expending so much energy on managing
appearances
on managing how people think about you
on managing and maintaining this this
image
you'll have zero time to actually make
money
make money first and then go back and
manage the appearances
again
this is why learning from Millionaires
and multi-millionaires is the dumbest
thing you can do
if you if you are not even making enough
money if they're telling you what they
what got them to be a Deca millionaire
or something like that they're going to
tell you manage your reputation tightly
screw that literally screw that that's
what I say
because the idea of daily managing
reputation is ridiculous
when it comes to this business
and yet you will hear
people talk about it all the time
your reputation listen my reputation
those that work with me know the results
that I get that's my reputation
my reputation is sometimes he goes off
and is a little bit wild with his energy
on social media great if somebody
chooses to not work with me because they
saw this podcast I don't with them
it's not my job to try to make them want
to work with me and want to like me and
want to think nice things about me and
try to tightly control how they perceive
me
I guarantee you every millionaire every
millionaire that I know what got them
from zero to six figures is they stopped
caring what everybody thought about them
and they stopped trying to control that
then once they started making a million
dollars they started to spend their
focus more on branding and things like
that but that's not what got them there
and it's a complete fallacy lie it's a
it's a it's a it's a mental
problem that people spend so much energy
on how they're perceived and branding in
the beginning branding doesn't matter
branding happens over time
in this business branding happens long
term in this business
I'm just I'm so saddened to see people
because literally this behavior that I'm
talking about on this podcast
will will have you spinning in circles
making zero dollars for 10 to 20 to 30
years in this business and you'll
constantly be like why can't they make
money in this business because literally
you are doing the opposite of what's
going to make you money
by operating in that way by being so
stinking scared you might say well I'm
not scared I'm confident no you're not
confident
if you're trying that stinking hard to
manage how people see you you're not
confident at all you don't believe in
yourself you you're confident in your
ability to manage and people's
perceptions of you you are confident and
believe that by doing that that will
produce success for you and I'm here to
tell you it will not and so stop
believing the lies that Society tells us
about success Stop Believing what
billionaire and millionaire memes say
out there and start actually doing what
it takes to be successful in the course
creation and coaching industry and
that's what I love helping people do is
to shine a spotlight on what actually
works because most people won't tell you
what actually works because they're too
concerned about looking perfect they're
too concerned about making themselves
appear perfect to everybody
focus on the five steps getting leads in
your business
don't worry about how they perceive you
don't worry about sounding perfect being
perfect appearing like a pro that people
will like the trust building process has
nothing to do with appearances
it has everything to do with
you making a connection with your Target
customer and them buying from you
and when you can do that
you can make millions of dollars
managing and maintaining
the opinions of people who will never
spend money with you
and trying to control how people
perceive you
will keep you broke
consistently getting leads in your
business
new sales
anything but that
trying to manage your reputation before
you even have one if you've never sold
anything in your business you have no
reputation and so you're trying too hard
to manage something that doesn't even
exist
psycho
like but that's most people
crazy
but it's most beginner newbie course
creators and coaches
is they believe that if I just look like
the successful millionaire coach if I
just do what they do then I'll be
successful and you got no clue what
you're doing
because you've never done it before
but this is what works when you remove
that shame filter from your brain and
you remove the fear of consequences the
fear of you saying something and
somebody misunderstanding you and it
turning out bad for you if you can
remove that from your brain entirely
you literally 10 and 100x your ability
to make money in courses and online
coaching
but we have a thousand and one reasons a
thousand one things that have happened
in our life a thousand and one traumas a
thousand to one horrible relationships
or friendships or we got people telling
us in our ear that we have to be a
certain way people literally who have no
experience in what we're doing giving us
opinions that don't actually work and
then we're wondering why is it not
working well have you actually done what
works
well no most people have it
and so if you can stop trying to manage
and maintain and control
how other people see you stop trying to
work so hard see here's the thing your
reputation has more to do with the
results that you produce
not
did he make me feel good
like
stop wasting your time
on stuff that won't produce an income
stop wasting your time on stuff that
won't add to your bottom line yes be
kind to people yes be caring yes connect
with people
but if you're spending like hours trying
to show and demonstrate that you're a
caring kind person and all of your time
is spent doing that and you spend no
time building a landing page or writing
your I mean I'm sorry but what are you
doing you're literally you're literally
just trying to make yourself feel good
inside and you're just doing feel good
activities because you feel like you're
obligated to do them because for some
reason somebody at some time in your
life told you that people who are
successful only do this
oh it's crazy to me I'm just like
there's a path that works that produces
results
our mindset foundations training
in the client growth accelerator walks
you through this we spent eight hours
together in an environment in a live
event that I did
and we walk you through the process of
working on your mindset this is one of
the huge biggest factors
that limits people from being successful
is they have a they have this filter on
their mouth and their words
and they have this filter
that is so concerned about making
everybody see them how they wish to be
seen
and that filter is the number one money
sucker I've ever seen
it manifests in so many different ways
it manifests as perfectionism it
manifests as but every but all it really
is is it's just great insecurity and
fear that's all it is
because it's fear that if we don't do
those things then things won't go well
for us
and I'm here to tell you by doing those
things you're making things not go well
for you
and when you give up and you stop being
so cautious all the time with everything
that you say and right and and so like
so careful to like
do and say all the right things and if
you say something that you're maybe
it'll be pursued the wrong way you
defend yourself and you disclaimer it
and you give a precursor like just just
and just just like if you removed the
amount of energy that you spend doing
that from your life completely forever
you would transform your relationships
in life
and that I hope that this encourages you
to do that because I used to be one of
those people
my early podcast episodes are even that
way
not anymore
it's not worth it
it's not going to grow my business it
hasn't grown my business my business
started to grow when I removed the
filter
and I stopped precursoring everything
and I stopped trying to over explain
everything over explaining
is is it's a massive wealth killer
over explaining is directly related to
fear worry usually related to something
painful to happen in our life when we
didn't over explain enough that
something bad happened and so then we
correlate over explaining
to success
and when you quit over explaining and
you just do and you don't worry about
what anybody thinks
that's where success starts to come in
all right everybody
listen I know this has been a passionate
episode I feel strongly about this
message I feel strongly about helping
you get it
and hopefully this has helped you get it
just a little bit more
if you want to make six figures or even
seven figures as a coach trainer or
Mentor online I'd love to help you do
that the client growth accelerator does
that you can join the waiting list for
it you can join one of the live events
that we're doing plus we have over 180
podcast episodes on this podcast and
almost a thousand videos on YouTube
there is no excuse and no reason for you
if you're a coach course grader trainer
or mentor to struggle to get clients
because we have figured out a proven
system that works if you work it
the only reason that you would be
struggling
is fear or Pride
and that's what I tell people you're
either too prideful to get the help you
need
great I can't help you
Pride's too
far up your butt for me to actually help
you
awesome or you're afraid
of
what might go wrong
and things not going your way and and
that can be solved
and you can break up with fear
I promise you every dream that you have
is directly on the other side of what
terrifies you the most
[Music]
and if you can
end
the constant internal battle struggle
with fear that tries to rip us apart and
tell us oh you shouldn't do this so you
should do that and tries to make us be
so cautious and timid all the time
when you can break up with that
internally
you can make a ton of money as a coach
or course creator
if you're constantly worried and fearful
you'll struggle because everything you
will stall before you even start on
every step because you'll over analyze
overthink and over explain everything to
the point that you are incapable there's
not enough hours in the day for you to
actually get done anything
when you're operating that way and so
that's why when you can learn to stop
overthinking and you'll learn to act
before you think or think and act
simultaneously
I love teaching people stop thinking
before you act
stop getting ready and then aiming
things
fire ready fire aim
fire
pull the trigger before you actually
have it aimed perfectly
that's the success strategy in this
business that's gonna radically change
your life
that's going to radically revolutionize
what you do and yet most people are so
scared or their pride is so
deep
they won't they they are incapable of
doing that
and that's what I love to help people do
that's what the podcast helps you with
and that's what my coaching program
helps people do is to start to build
their offers and get more leads get more
sales and get more clients because
that's the number one thing that you
need to do in your business to get
results and I'd love to help you do that
great life everybody we'll talk soon